### NAVEEN KUMAR N

@9600265620

naveen2426kumar@gmail.com

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Experienced Full Stack Developer with 2.5= years of experience and a degree in Computer Science. Expert in Angular and React js with experience in versions above Angular 5. Skilled in Node.js, Express Js,HTML, CSS, and Agile methodologies

### **SKILL SETS:**

- Angular 6+, React JS, React Redux,
- Typescript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SCSS,
- Node JS, Express JS, Mongo dB, MySQL, Web3 JS

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

## **INFOSYS LIMITED - Senior System Engineer** (Sep 2022 – Till)

- Developing Angular Libraries for main frame applications.
- Extensively trained and experienced in Main Frame Stream.
- · Issued recommendations to company regarding necessary upgrades on websites
- Experience in **US Baking applications** and terminologies

## SPARKOUT TECH SOLUTIONS -Associate Full Stack Developer (Feb 2022 -Aug 2022)

- Collaborate well with engineers, researchers, and data implementation specialists to design and create advanced, elegant and efficient systems
- Experience on Cloud deployments with **Node js** applications. Effective knowledge on cloud application and deployment stages.
- Experience in **Blockchain** and **crypto** API integration.

### **IONSTAR India Pvt Ltd - Full Stack Developer** (May 2020 – Oct 2021)

- Experience on MEAN Stack applications,
- Developing Node Js , Angular and React Js applications
- Building interactive consumer data from multiple systems and RESTfull abstract to the UI through a Node.s backend

# **ROLES AND RESPONSIBITIES**

- Develop, test, and deploy fast and scaleable web apps
- Designing and maintenance of fully functional large relational and non-relational databases
- Timely deployment of web apps on the cloud
- Server management and cloud-based infrastructure
- Establishment and integration of development tools as required
- App deployment on the cloud along with solving debugging issues
- Coding architecture for frontend and backend
- Implement tasks in accordance with schedule budget goals
- Communication with clients and satisfying their needs

### **CERTIFICATION COURSE:**

- Professional Angular certification,
- Certification On Python
- MEAN stack Developer Course
- React Redux

# **PROJECT**

Developed a projects

• "AUTONOMOUS CAR WITH DATA PRIVACY AND SECURITY",

An Autonomous car can pass data with help of Customized Neural Engine

"SMART SURVEILLANCE",

An Surveillance system having AI Abilities

• "SOCIAL MEDIA SECURITY USING TESSERACT",

Using Tesseract OCR providing image sense security to the user

• "PASSPORT AUTOMATION SYSTEM USING PHP".

Automating passport system with SQL and php

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:**

B. E(Computer Science and Engineering)- Erode Sengunthar Engineering College -(2016-2020)- 74%

### **STRENGTH:**

Leadership

Lead team of 5 developers to complete a project ahead of schedule.

Problem-solving

Developed solution to reduce load time of web app by 50%.

Communication

Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure successful project completion.

### **PERSONAL PROFILE:**

Father's Name
Date of Birth
Jan 24, 1997
Age
25 Years.
Marital Status
Single

Known Language : English, Tamil

• Nationality : Indian

• Hobby : Listening music, Drawing

• Address : 63, Kulanthai Velan street, Dindigul-624001

# **DECLARATION**

I here by declare that above all said information is true to the best of my knowledge.

(NAVEENKUMAR N)